WILLEM N. ELSDON

■ willelsdon@gmail.com | 4 909-202-3855 | In willem-elsdon | • welsdon | • Boise, Idaho

SUMMARY: A highly motivated systems engineer with an active TS/SCI clearance and over three years of experience in **mechanical design**, systems engineering, and software quality assurance. My goal is to join a rewarding and collaborative team where I can implement my diverse set of skills and passion for firearms in an industry leading company such as PWS.

Professional Experience

Raytheon Intelligence & Space — Systems Engineer II IV&T — SEIT

February 2022 - Present

- Lead daily Scrums via **Jira** with the IV&T team and brainstorm solutions to story blockers with leadership
- Create new feature files used in automation, leveraging Gherkin syntax and Visual Studio Code via VDIs
- Verify Discrepancy Reports (DR's) from creation to final integration, review pull requests using **BitBucket**
- Assist coordinating test plans and events for Integrated Master Schedule (IMS) milestones using Jira and Confluence
- Frequently travel to sites to help integrate the FORGE system, requires extensive cross-product collaboration
 Systems Engineering SEIT
- Spearheaded an initiative to overhaul and polish the MBSE model of the FORGE system while following SysML
- The final iteration resulted in a scalable and future proof representation of the system that adheres to DoDAF architecture
- Developed scripts (Apache VTL) for use with CAMEO that captures necessary information for customer facing documentation
- Led various customer meetings (Technical Exchange Meetings, **TEMs**), verifying requirements were met and appropriate actions were in place to meet the demands of those slated for completion

Raytheon Intelligence & Space — Systems Engineer I IV&T — SEIT

July 2020 - February 2022

- Wrote technical documentation (Test Cases, Integration Cases, Test Procedures) for new capabilities added to a legacy program, ensuring the requirements outlined in **DOORS** were achieved
- Participated in customer facing test events for requirement verification (ran, collected, and verified results)
- Brought new and updated documentation through review (review boards & critical review meetings)
- Troubleshot and documented all encountered issues using ClearQuest and root-cause analysis

Western Aircraft — $Engineering\ Intern$

OCTOBER 2019 - APRIL 2020

Avionics — Mechanical

- Utilized Solidworks to design tooling used in the repair and maintenance of private aircraft (Pilatus, Beechcraft, Dassault Falcon)
- Helped engineer solutions for the upgrade and repair of avionics, leveraging ANSI drawings that outlined installation and removal
- Held one on one meetings with the Chief Engineer to review my drawings, discuss improvments, and create redlines
- Communicated with FAA DER's to validate designs, once validated I worked with A&P mechanics throughout installation
- Took accurate physical measurements of aircraft internals to identify ideal mounting and repair locations for the imrpoved avionics
- Created drawings for maintenance tools of private aircraft, once the **BOM** was complete, obtained quotes from local companies

Northrop Grumman — Composites Structure Design Intern (F-35) Ducts & Doors — Mechanical

May 2019 - Aug 2019

- Collaborated with managerial and engineering staff to determine optimal solutions (using CATIA V5 and Fibersim) to repair composite parts damaged during the manufacturing process for the air inlet ducts of the F-35 Joint Strike Fighter
- Communicated these repairs directly to Liaison Engineers where they were implemented immediately
- Revised three Material and Process specifications to create a more efficient manufacturing procedure and successfully presented them to the Office of Chief Engineers
- $\bullet \ \ {\rm Organized} \ \ {\rm all} \ \ {\rm previous} \ \ {\rm repair} \ \ {\rm acquisition} \ \ {\rm and} \ \ {\rm less} \ \ {\rm manufacturing} \ \ {\rm downtime}$

EDUCATION

Mechanical Engineering — Bachelor of Science

MAY 2020 GPA: 3.7

Boise State University - Boise, Idaho

Gem Scholarship Recipient, SWE Member, ME Club Treasurer, Concrete Canoe

Air Quality Lab — Research Assistant

- Utilized Excel, interpreted PM2.5 and PM10 data that was gathered during the summer of 2017 within the Treasure Valley
- Data was collected using state-of-the-art MOUDI II devices which helped analyze solutions to minimizing the production of fine particulate matter, and what could be done as a short term solution
- Presented my findings to Boise State engineering faculty where my paper has since been used as a template for future reports

Skills

 Solidworks, Fusion 360, Change Management, Root Cause Analysis, Adaptability, Attention to Detail, Mechanically Inclined, CameoEA, Linux, Atlassian, Excel, Scrum Master, Technical Writing & Communication, Visual Studio Code, SysML, Customer Interaction, Troubleshooting, DOORS, Requirement Verification, MBSE, Quality Assurance, Log analysis, USPSA CO B Class